A Guide to the R. Bolling Batte Papers, 1918-1992
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
R. Bolling Batte Papers, 1918-1992
Library of Virginia
35260
29.6 cubic feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Robert Bolling Batte IV, Salisbury, North Carolina, 5 February 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Bolling Batte was born in Norfolk, Virginia on 13 August 1906. In 1928, he graduated from Virginia Military Institute. He was employed as an engineer at the C & P Telephone Co. and later earned an LL.B. degree from Virginia College of Law. He was a resident of Richmond, Virginia. He died in Petersburg, Virginia on 3 June 1996 and was buried in Elmwood Cemetery, Norfolk, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Genealogical research files of Robert Bolling Batte, including family research files, subject files and county research notes, extensive information on the Batte, Brodnax, Ingram, Epes/Eppes and Jones families, and biographical card files. Also contained in the collection is information which was compiled by Augusta B. Fothergill (Augusta Bridgland Middleton Fothergill, 1876-1965) and Alice L. Ingram (Alice Littlepage Ingram, 1891-1982). Every effort was made during processing of the collection to maintain the original order of the materials. In some cases, information amassed by all three individuals can be found in the same folder.
Organization
Organized into the following seven series: I. Family research files. II. Subject files and county research notes. III. Batte files. IV. Brodnax/Ingram files. V. Epes/Eppes files. VI. Jones files. VII. Biographical card files.
Contents List
- Family Research Files (Box 1-22)
  The family research files contain genealogical notes abstracted from court records, including deed books, order books, will books and marriage records. There is a substanial amount of information on the Blow, Bolling, Drummond, Harrison, Jones, Lee, Lewis, Moseley, Poythress, Smith and Willis families. Families researched are from all over Virginia, but there is a particular emphasis on those from Amelia, Brunswick, Dinwiddie, Lunenburg, Nottoway, Prince George and Sussex Counties. The majority of this group of records were compiled by Augusta B. Fothergill.
  - A - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abney (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alexander (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alfriend (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allan (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allmand (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ambler (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrews (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Archer (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Armistead (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ashby (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ashton (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Atkinson (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austin (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aylette (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - B - General (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bacon (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bailey (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baird (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baker (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baker of Norfolk (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ball (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ballard (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Banister (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Barber (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Barham (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Barnard/Bernard (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Barnes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Barrow (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Barton (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Baskerville (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bass (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bassett (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bathurst (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Battaile (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Batte Family (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Batte Family - Misc. Correspondence with (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Batte of Prince George - Clippings II (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Batts (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baugh (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Baylor (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Beasley (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bedford (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Behethland (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bell (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bennett (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bernard (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Berryman (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Beverley (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bevil/Bevill (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Binns (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Blair (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bland (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bland Material (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Blow (Box 3, Folder 3-9)
  - Blow Family - Pencil Copy (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Blunt (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Boisseau (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bolling (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bolling - Centre Hill (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bolling - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bolling - Colin James (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bolling - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bolling - Correspondence with Bradley (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bolling - Permanant Material, Pictures, etc. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bolling - Working Material (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Booker (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Booth (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Boothe (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bott (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Boulden (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bowling (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Boyd (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Boykin (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bradley (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Bragg (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Branch (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Brander (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Braxton (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Breckenridge (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Brent (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Briggs (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Britton (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Broaddus (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Brockenbrough (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Brodnax (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Brodnax - Memphis, TN (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Brodnax, Thomas Hall (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Bronaugh (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brooke (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bryan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Brydon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Burwell (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bushrod (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Byrd (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Byrd - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - C - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cabell (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Calloway (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Calvert (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Campbell (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cargill (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Carr (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Carrington (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Carter (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Carter (Thomas) Line (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carter Clippings (All Va. Lines) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cary (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Catlett (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Chamberlayne (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Champion (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Chandler (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Chapman (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Chappell (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cheves (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Chew (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Chew - Account Book of R. P. Chew, 1878-1891 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chilton (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Christian (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clack (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clack of Brunswick (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Claiborne (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clark (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Clarke (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Clements (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cobb/Cobbs (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cocke (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cocke of Hanover (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cocke Clippings (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cockes and Cousins - Set #1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cockes and Cousins - Set #2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Coleman (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Coles (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Collier (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Conway (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cook (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cooke (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cooksey (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Copland (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Corbin (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Covington (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cox (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Cox/Gregory/Lyne (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Crawley/Crallé (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Crews (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Cross (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Crump (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - D - General (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Dabney (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Dade (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Dandridge (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Daniel (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Davidson (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Dean (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Degraffenreidt (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Delony (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dickinson (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Digges (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Dillard (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Doswell (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Downman (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Drew (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Drummond (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Drummond Material (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Drummond Clippings (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Dudley (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dunn (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - E - General (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Eaton (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Echols (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Edmunds (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Edwards (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Eggleston (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Elam (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Eldridge (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Elliott (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ellyson (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Eskridge (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Eustace (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Evans (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - F - General (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Fairfax (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Farrar (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Faulkner (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fauntleroy (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Feild (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Finney (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Fitzgerald (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Fitzhugh (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Fleming (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Fletcher (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Flood (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Flournoy (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Floyd (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Fontaine (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Fort (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Fothergill (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Fothergill Family Letters - Middleton, Naugle, Bridgland (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Fowlkes (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - French - Clippings (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - French, S. Bassett (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - French, S. Bassett - Notes (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Friend (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - G - General (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Galt (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Garland (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Garnett (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Garrett (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Gates (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - George (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Gibson (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Gilliam (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Goodman/Goodwin (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Goodrich (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Goodwin (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Goodwyn (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Gookin (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Gordon (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Grammer (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Grant (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Gravatt (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Graves (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Gray (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Grayson (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Green, Dr. Bennett (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Green of Prince George County (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Green of Warwick County (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Greenhill (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Greenlee (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Gregory (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Gresham (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Grigg (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Grigsby (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Grinnan (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Grymes (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Gunn (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - H - General (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hairston (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hall (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hamlin (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hampton (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hancock (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hansford (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hardaway (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hardy (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Harwood (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Harris (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Harris (From Ingram) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Harrison of Berkeley and Brandon (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Harrison (Brunswick) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Harrison (James River) (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Harrison of Prince George (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Harrison of Sussex (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Harrison of York, Westmoreland, and Richmond Counties (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Harrison, Burr - Stafford and Prince William Counties (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Harrison Papers (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Harrison Clippings (All Lines) (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Harrison - Misc. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Hartwell (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Harvie/Harvey (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Haskins (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hatcher (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Haynie (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Heath (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Henderson (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Henry (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Herndon (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hicks/Jones/Morrison/Harrison/Conrad Genealogical Material Obtained from Mrs. Browder (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hicks - Robert Line of Brunswick (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hicks - Misc. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hill (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hinton (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hite (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hobson (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Holt (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hooe (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Hoomes (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hopkins (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Hubbard (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
  - Hubbard of York and Buckingham Counties (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Humphrey (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Hunter (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Hutcheson (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - I - General (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ingram (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ingram, Alice Littlepage (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Irby (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Irby of Nottoway (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - J - General (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Stonewall Jackson (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Jarratt (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - Jefferson (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Jefferson Clippings (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Jennings (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Jett (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Johnson (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Jolly (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Jones (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Jones Chart (To Be Typed) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Jones of Morrison, Va. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Jones of Warwick - Part I (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Jones of Warwick - Part II (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Jones of Warwick - Real Property (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Roger Churchill Jones (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Jones Clippings (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Jordan (Box 13, Folder 24-25)
  - K - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Keeling (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Kemp (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Kennon (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Key (Not Francis Scott Key) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - King (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Knox (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - L - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Lamb (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Land (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Langhorne - Nancy (Langhorne) Astor - Lady Astor (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Lanier (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Ledbetter (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Lea/Lee (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Lee (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
  - Lee - General Robert Edward Lee - Clippings (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Lee (Hugh) (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
  - Lee, Henry of York County (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Lees of Stratford Line (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Lee- Stratford Manor (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Lee Clippings (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Leftwich (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Leigh (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Lewis (Howell) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lewis (John of Point Pleasant and Margaret Lynn Lewis) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Lewis of Amelia and Pittsylvania (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lewis of Warner Hall (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lewis - Misc. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lewis (Misc. Correspondence From "Hopefuls" Contributing Nothing (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lewis Clippings (All Branches) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Ligon (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Nancy Hawks Lincoln (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Linton (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Little (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Littlepage (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Lloyd (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Logan (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Long - Koontz (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Lound (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Lovett (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lucas (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lucy (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Lunsford (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Lyle - General (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Lyle (Removal of Graveyard at "Summer Hill") (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Lyne (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - M - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Maben (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Maclin (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Macon (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Madison (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Mallory (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Marks (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Marsden (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Marshall (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Marshall - Clippings (All Branches) (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Mason (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Mason II (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Mason of Norfolk and Surry (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - George Mason of Gunston Hall (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Mason of Stafford Line (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Nicholson - Mason (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Maury (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - May (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Mayo (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Mc - General (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - McGuire (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - McIlwaine (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - McMurran (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - McRae (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Meade (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Meriwether (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Miller (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Miller - J.P. Madison Papers (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Minor (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Mitchell (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Montague (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Moore (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Morrison (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Moseley (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Moseley (Clayton Torrence Extracts) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Moseley (Court Records) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Moseley - Misc. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Moseley - To Be Sorted (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Moss (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Munford (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Murat (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - N - General (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Neblett (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Nelson (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Newton (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Newton of Norfolk (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Nimmo (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Norton (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - O - General (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Osborne (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - P - Misc. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Page (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Parham (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Parrott (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Patteson (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Patterson (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - The Paynes of Virginia by Brooke Payne (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Peachy (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Pegram (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Pendleton (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Peterson (Box 17, Folder 29-30)
  - Peterson - Prince George Records (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Peyton (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Poague Book - The Descendants of John Poague (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Poindexter (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Power (Alice Ingram) (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Poythress (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Poythress - Binders (Flowerdew Hundred) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Poythress Chart (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Poythress (P-1) Chart (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Poythress - County Record Extracts (Amelia, Surry, Petersburg, Sussex) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Poythress of Brunswick and Mecklenburg (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Poythress - Extracts from Charles City Records (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Poythress - Extracts from Prince George Records (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Poythress - Extracts from Printed Material (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Poythress Material from Miss Peebles (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Poythress Notes - 2nd Set (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Poythress - Old "142" Charts (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Poythress - Peebles Notes (Not Checked) (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Poythress - Photo Records (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Poythress - Sources and Index (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Poythress - Surveys (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Poythress Will, 1724 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Poythress - Write Up Drafts (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Preston (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Pretlow (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Price (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Pryor (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - R - General (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Randolph (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Randolph, Henry (Alice Ingram) (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - William Randolph P16 Extracts (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Richards (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Rives (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Robertson (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Robertson (Alice Ingram) (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Royall (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Ruffin (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ruffin (Alice Ingram) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - S - General (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Scott (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Selden (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Shield (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Shippey (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Shore (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Short (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Sinclair (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Smart (Alice Ingram) (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Smith (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Smith - Richard Hewlett, Sydney Strother, et al. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Smith, Richard of Amelia and Lunenburg (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Smith of Brunswick (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Smith of Essex (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Smith of Gloucester and York (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Isham Smith - Surry, Sussex (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Smith - Brockenbrough - Lamb (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Southall (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Spotswood (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Stainback (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Starke (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Stith (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Stokes (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Stratton (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Strother - French (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Sturdivant (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Syme (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - T - Misc. (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Tabb (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Talcott (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Taliaferro (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Tanner (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Tatem (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Tatum (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Taylor (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Taylor (Alice Ingram) (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Taylor, Daniel (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Taylor, William (Alice Ingram) (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Thweatt (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Thornton (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Thorogood (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Thruston (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Todd (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Travis (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Trezevant (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Trezevant - Huguenot Papers for Gardiner Boothe (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Trigg (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Tucker (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Turnbull (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Turpin (Alice Ingram) (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Tyler (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - U - General (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Upshur (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - V - Misc. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Valentine (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - W - General (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Walke (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Walker (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Walker I (Alice Ingram) (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Walker II (Alice Ingram) (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Walker, Henry (Alice Ingram) (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Wallace (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Waller (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Walthall (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Walthall - Mrs. Spicer (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Ward (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Washington (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Watson (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Augustus Watson & Wilson (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - West (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Whitaker (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Whitaker, Rev. William (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - White (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Whiting (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Whittle (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Willcox (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Williams (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Willis of Brunswick (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Willis - Henry of Fredericksburg (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Willis - Goochland (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Willis of Henrico (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Willis - Mecklenburg (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Willis Clippings (All Lines) (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Willis - Correspondence (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Willis - General (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Willis Records - 17th Century (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Willis - Misc. Records (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Willson (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Wilson (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Winston (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Wise (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Withers (Alice Ingram) (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Abraham Wood of Charles City (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Wood, Coralie Gregory (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Wood of Warwick (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Woodhouse (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Woodson (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Worsham (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Wyatt (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Wynne (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Yates (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Yeardley (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Young - Surry & Brunswick (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Young of Warwick (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Zehmer (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - X-Y-Z - Clippings (Box 21, Folder 34)
- Subject Files and County Research Notes (Box 22-33)
  The subject files and county research notes also include abstracts from court records, as well as correspondence, clippings, tombstone inscriptions, pedigree charts and published works. This group of records is largely the work of R. Bolling Batte.
  - Addresses (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
  - Albemarle County Marriages (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Amelia Census (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Amelia County Marriages (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Amelia County Records (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Amherst Census (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Askew, Margaret (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bedford Marriage Bonds (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Berkeley County Records (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Beverley Book Index Project (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - The Beverely Family of Virginia - Index (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Bible Records (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Borrowed Material From Mary Douthat (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Borrowed Material to Return (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Bristol Parish Project (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Bristol Parish Register (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Browder, Barbara (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Brunswick Census (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Brunswick County Records (Box 22, Folder 22)